<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ash Drake</title>
    <link>https://aldra.co/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ash Drake</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aldra.co/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New To Programming - Good Resources To Get Started</title>
      <link>https://aldra.co/blog/where-to-start-new-to-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aldra.co/blog/where-to-start-new-to-programming/</guid>
      <description>I often get emails from new developers who are looking to transition into tech, but not quite sure where or how to get started. It is a challenge that I have also faced myself - I also started learning to code several years ago, feeling overwhelmed with all of the options, and having little to no context to help choose between them. Should I do a bootcamp? Which bootcamp should I do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Hugo Structured Data to Build a Resume Page</title>
      <link>https://aldra.co/blog/hugo_structured_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aldra.co/blog/hugo_structured_data/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how I built my Resume page using Hugo&amp;rsquo;s data directory functionality.
I have enjoyed using Hugo to set up a blog. I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly enjoy design and layout, so a system that allows me to do that one time, while still outputting an cheap-to-host static site, is nice to work with.
I wanted to set up a resume page, and give myself more control over the design than I would have using Markdown/CSS &amp;ndash; treating the resume as a collection of data, instead of a piece of content, provided that flexibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Rebase Tricks: Rebase Interactive</title>
      <link>https://aldra.co/blog/git_rebase_tricks_interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 10:04:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aldra.co/blog/git_rebase_tricks_interactive/</guid>
      <description>I have been using the git rebase command heavily lately, and thought it might be good to write a quick tips and tricks guide about it. I have found it incredibly useful for keeping my git history clean, organizing my thoughts about what I am writing and why, and grouping changes together as logical groups.
Why would I want to use this? First, it might be useful to motivate why this tool is helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 1</title>
      <link>https://aldra.co/updates/mar012020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 21:27:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aldra.co/updates/mar012020/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently signed on to help out more with Exercism, by becoming a maintainer for the Python track. I&amp;rsquo;m still figuring out how to work on such a large project; this past weekend I managed to send an email &amp;amp; Github ping that should have gone to my subteam of 3-5 Python maintainers, to the whole (150 people) group of maintainers; I messed something up trying to rebase from master and it was gross.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dec 2</title>
      <link>https://aldra.co/updates/dec042019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 21:34:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aldra.co/updates/dec042019/</guid>
      <description>Advent of Code: trying to solve all the puzzles this year, in multiple languages if I can. Unicorn Project: recently finished and working on a review (sequel to Phoenix Project) Bathrobe: my preschooler wants one, so I&amp;rsquo;m sewing one. Sabbatical: mostly enjoying time to bake, exercise, and relax. Half Marathon: I&amp;rsquo;m training for a half marathon in January, and have been reading a lot about heart rate training and altitude (I live at 6k+ ft above sea level).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Folder Structure and Naming Conventions</title>
      <link>https://aldra.co/blog/git_naming_and_folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 16:24:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aldra.co/blog/git_naming_and_folders/</guid>
      <description>Recently at work, I ran into one of those once-in-a-while git issues that generally end up being solved with creative Googling and git magic. This time, though, I wanted to understand a little more about how git works.
The problem I was developing a new feature with a colleague, so we had two branches going that we were rebasing against each other as we went.
feature-name/my-branch feature-name/his-branch At some point, we decided it was time to merge our branches into one consolidated effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://aldra.co/blog/python-iter-iterator-iterables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aldra.co/blog/python-iter-iterator-iterables/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://aldra.co/blog/where-to-start-preparing-for-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aldra.co/blog/where-to-start-preparing-for-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Tips for algorithmic interviews
 say what you do know, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t know something else handle edge cases (empty list, negative numbers, zero, None, etc) use descriptive variables where possible (avoid i/j)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume | Ash Drake</title>
      <link>https://aldra.co/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aldra.co/resume/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
